Objective

I am looking for a role the games industry that would give me the opportunity to work with ActionScript 3 and object-oriented JavaScript.

Skill Sets

ActionScript (AS) 3, $2 \& 1 \sim$ Good working knowledge of the native capabilities of the Flash Player. Good working knowledge of the drawing and animation tools available in the Flash authoring-environment. Developed the Edmodo document-viewer written in AS3 using FlashDevelop and the Flex compiler.

3D Modeling & Image Manipulation ~ Experienced with using Maya, 3DS Max & Z-Brush to produce both organic & hard-surface models. Extensively used PhotoShop for image manipulation, mostly in regards to creating & editing texture maps.

JavaScript (Object-Oriented) ~ At Edmodo I was the advocate for writing a class-based JS library allowing us to more easily organize & reuse code. I also developed a system for packaging individual class files into larger deployment files.

PHP ~ Worked with the Zend framework & wrote SQL for database interaction.

Employment History

Edmodo.com (Fusion Project Inc.) Mountain View, CA ~ Web Developer ~ March 2009 - Present

Edmodo is an online social learning platform for teachers and students that receives over 35,000 daily visits. As the only full-time front-end developer, I pioneered the use of a class-based JS library allowing us to more easily organize and reuse code. I also developed the Edmodo document-viewer written in AS3.

Saffron Interactive London, UK ~ Multimedia Developer ~ April 2002 – October 2005

- ActionScript, ASP/VB Script, JavaScript & Director-Lingo development
- 3D modeling, texturing, animation & rendering
- Design of educational interactions & diagrams
- HTML/CSS & Flash layout
- Client interaction

Projects

Hilton Hotels - Web Site Content Management Training, Siemens PG – Turbine Inspection Guide,
Lord Chancellor's Department / Central Office of Information - Document Management System Guide,
British Telecom (BT) – Health & Safety, T-Mobile – Employee Orientation, Cemex - (cement-info), DHL - Preparing for
Interviews Training Course, Britannia Royal Naval College – 3D Marketing Demo, BT - Indirect Channels 2, Sales Training
Tool, BT - Customer Satisfaction Training Module, BT - Line Managers Guide, Churchill - 3D e-Learning Interface Demo,
BT - Evolve, BT - Way, BT - TAS, Ladbrokes - Racing Start, Induction program, Liberator - 3D Marketing Demo

Colourmation Media Ltd. Kingston, UK ~ Multimedia/Web Developer ~ June 1997 – March 2002

- ActionScript, ASP/VB Script, JavaScript & Director-Lingo development
- 3D modeling, texturing, animation & rendering
- HTML/CSS

Projects

KBR / Halliburton – Varris Deep-Sea Pump Animations, **British Petroleum (BP)** ETAP Intranet Site, **BP** Emergency Procedure Intranet Site, **Shell** ETAP promotional animation, **Shell** ETAP information CD-ROM, **BP** in Algeria – Public Relations Site, **Kerr McGee** Janice Field Development Site Information Poster

Education

ACADEMY OF ART UNIVERSITY (2007-2008) – San Francisco, USA ~ Personal Enrichment Classes: Organic Modeling, Intermediate Figure Drawing, Basic Figure Drawing, Figure Modeling, Maya 1, Analysis of Form